import { Question } from './question';

export const QUESTIONS: Question[] = [
	{
		question: 'By area, which country is the considered the second largest in the world, to Russia?',
		category: 'Geography',
		answers: [ 'Azerbaijan', 'Canada', 'United States', 'Russia', 'China' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Canada'
	},
	{
		question: 'The characteristic color of a shiny coffee thermos is designed to prevent heat loss by which of the following processes?',
		category: 'Heat Exchange',
		answers: [ 'Convection', 'Radiation', 'Slow Diffusion', 'Conduction', 'Circulation' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Radiation'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which native Denakk’e name for the Alaskan peak Mount McKinley means “The High One?”',
		category: 'Location, Location',
		answers: [ 'Yukon', 'Kenai', 'Denali', 'Kuyokuk', 'Whittier' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Denali'
	},
	{
		question: 'While humans have recently accelerated the greenhouse effect, which mostly non-human created gas contributes most to this process?',
		category: 'Got Some Gas',
		answers: [ 'Water vapor', 'Ozone', 'Carbon Dioxide', 'Nitrous Oxide', 'Chlorofluorocarbons' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Water vapor'
	},
	{
		question: 'The largest object in our asteroid belt, named after the Roman goddess of agriculture, is the namesake of which chemical element?',
		category: 'Astronomy, Chemistry, and Mythology',
		answers: [ 'Cerium', 'Iridium', 'Plutonium', 'Samarium', 'Palladium' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Cerium'
	},
	{
		question: 'This modern crop is a domesticated teosinte developed by early Mesoamericans which can be found in foods such as nshima, chicha, and angu…',
		category: 'Monocots',
		answers: [ 'Rice', 'Sugarcane', 'Maize', 'Wheat', 'Millet' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Maize'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which city-state, located on the west bank of the Tiber River, is renowned for its basilica and obelisk? ',
		category: 'Autonomy',
		answers: [ 'Monaco', 'Qatar', 'Liechtenstein', 'Vatican City', 'Kuwait' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Vatican City'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which opera by Gioachino Rossini features Figaro, a tonsorial artist who resides in one of Spain’s largest cities?',
		category: 'Figaro! Figaro! Figaro!',
		answers: [ 'Carmen', 'The Marriage of Figaro', 'The Magic Flute', 'Don Giovanni', 'The Barber of Seville' ],
		correctAnswer: 'The Barber of Seville'
	},
	{
		question: 'The architectural period developed during and named after the reign of an iconic royal figure of the late 19th century is…',
		category: 'Architecture',
		answers: [ 'Georgian', 'Art deco', 'Victorian', 'Edwardian', 'Federal' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Victorian'
	},
	{
		question: 'This Newbery Medal winner is a bildungsroman about a boy and an abused dog who form a bond in West Virginia…',
		category: 'A Bildungsroman',
		answers: [ 'Bud, Not Buddy', 'The Giver', 'The Whipping Boy', 'Shiloh', 'Holes' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Shiloh'
	},
	{
		question: 'Aired from 1972 to 1985, this tv series was created by a famous American comedian based on a junkyard gang…',
		category: 'Oldies',
		answers: [ 'Fat Albert and the Cosby Kids', 'The Brady Bunch', 'Mister Rodger’s Neighborhood', 'Rugrats', 'Chalkzone' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Fat Albert and the Cosby Kids'
	},
	{
		question: 'In 2011, the fourth most powerful earthquake ever recorded triggered a tsunami which caused nuclear meltdowns in three reactors in this country…',
		category: 'Meltdowns',
		answers: [ 'United States', 'Japan', 'Indonesia', 'Chile', 'Russia' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Japan'
	},
	{
		question: 'Choose the state that seceded latest during the American civil war.',
		category: 'Confederates',
		answers: [ 'South Carolina', 'Mississippi', 'Iowa', 'Arkansas', 'Florida' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Arkansas'
	},
	{
		question: 'The Endangered Species Act is carried out in the USA by...',
		category: 'Agencies',
		answers: [ 'Fish and Wildlife Service', 'General Land Office', 'Bureau of Land Management', 'Department of Energy', 'National Park Service' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Fish and Wildlife Service'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following illnesses is now rare in developed countries due to widespread vaccination?',
		category: 'Illnesses',
		answers: [ 'Emphysema', 'Dengue fever', 'Septicemia', 'Melanoma', 'Diphtheria' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Diphtheria'
	},
	{
		question: 'Choose the option which is not a computer operating system.',
		category: 'Software',
		answers: [ 'PC DOS', 'AMD', 'Red Hat', 'Ubuntu', 'OS X' ],
		correctAnswer: 'AMD'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following appears in a popular meditation which states \'No man is an island\'?',
		category: 'Poetry',
		answers: [ 'How do I love thee?', 'Upon the slimy sea', 'Every man is a piece of the continent', 'Many times I had walked that way', 'With you I shall always be' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Every man is a piece of the continent'
	},
	{
		question: 'The five-hole is a term for the area between the goaltender’s legs in which of the following sports?',
		category: 'Sports',
		answers: [ 'Soccer', 'Ice Hockey', 'Bowling', 'Rugby', 'Water polo' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Ice Hockey'
	},
	{
		question: 'Choose the location that is not in Africa.',
		category: 'Geography',
		answers: [ 'Sao Tome', 'Senegal', 'Sierra Leone', 'San Marino', 'Seychelles' ],
		correctAnswer: 'San Marino'
	},
	{
		question: 'Can you spot the crossword answer that is not correctly paired with its meaning?',
		category: 'Crossword Anyone?',
		answers: [ 'Alga - Taj Mahal city', 'Zarf - Cup holder', 'Torte - A dense cake ', 'Olid - Foul smelling', 'Smee - Hook’s assistant' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Alga - Taj Mahal city'
	},
	{
		question: 'Complete the square for x^2 + 12x + 27 = 0 to find which of the following could equal 3.',
		category: 'Math',
		answers: [ '(x+3)', '(x+12)', '(x + 6)', '(x+36)', '(x+27)' ],
		correctAnswer: '(x + 6)'
	},
	{
		question: 'A molecule with 3 bonding domains and no free pairs of electrons can be classified as...',
		category: 'Chemistry Geometry',
		answers: [ 'Bent', 'Tetrahedral', 'Trigonal Planar', 'Linear', 'Square' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Trigonal Planar'
	},
	{
		question: 'This animated television series premiered in 1989 and is the longest running scripted program in television history with 574 episodes to date. Name the show that takes place in the fictional town of Springfield and follows a working class family of five?',
		category: 'Television, and Popular Culture',
		answers: [ 'Family Guy', 'Futurama', 'Spongebob Squarepants', 'The Simpsons', 'South Park' ],
		correctAnswer: 'The Simpsons'
	},
	{
		question: 'The world\'s largest swimming pool, San Alfonso del Mar, covers 20 acres and is composed of treated sea water from the pacific ocean. Name the country in which you can enjoy a dip among the 66 million liters of water in this man made marvel.',
		category: 'Recreation and Landmarks',
		answers: [ 'United States', 'Chile', 'New Zealand', 'Panama', 'Fiji' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Chile'
	},
	{
		question: 'La Tomatina is an annual festival where individuals throw tomatoes at each other on the last Wednesday of August every year. In which European city is this event held?',
		category: 'Food Fight',
		answers: [ 'Lisbon, Portugal', 'Buñol, Spain', 'Berlin, Germany', 'Sydney, Australia', 'Paris, France' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Buñol, Spain'
	},
	{
		question: 'For an airplane flying at a constant height, which force directly opposes the thrust?',
		category: 'Physics',
		answers: [ 'Weight', 'Roll', 'Pitch', 'Drag', 'Static Friction' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Drag'
	},
	{
		question: 'This herbivorous dinosaur\'s name translates to "deceptive lizard", though the true deception occured two years after its initial naming, when paleontologist Othniel Charles Marsh believed a specimen of it to be of a different species. Name this sauropod from the Jurassic period, which has also been given the name "Brontosaurus"',
		category: 'Dinosaurs',
		answers: [ 'Apatosaurus', 'Brachiosaurus', 'Carnotaurus', 'Deinonychus', 'Velociraptor' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Apatosaurus'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following counties has a flag with the sames colors as the United States\' flag?',
		category: 'Flags',
		answers: [ 'Canada', 'Germany', 'Spain', 'Italy', 'Russia' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Russia'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following greek letters is used in mathematics to represent the ratio of a circle\'s circumference to its RADIUS?',
		category: 'Math',
		answers: [ 'Alpha', 'Pi', 'Xi', 'Tau', 'Omicron' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Tau'
	},
	{
		question: 'What does the acronym GMAT stand for in regards to standardized testing?',
		category: 'Tests',
		answers: [ 'Graduate Management Admission Test', 'Graduate Marketing Aptitude Test', 'Greek Mathematical Advacement Test', 'General Management Aptitude Test', 'Graduate Medical Admission Test' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Graduate Management Admission Test'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following counties is doubly land-locked? (as in completely surrounded by land-locked countries)',
		category: 'Geography',
		answers: [ 'Mongolia', 'Ukraine', 'Uzbekistan', 'Chad', 'Paraguay' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Uzbekistan'
	},
	{
		question: 'What was the name of Pope Francis before he became Pope?',
		category: 'Famous People',
		answers: [ 'Karol Jozef Wojtla', 'Jorge Mario Bergoglio', 'Angelo Giuseppe Roncalli', 'Alessandro Farnese', 'Giovanni Battista Montini' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Jorge Mario Bergoglio'
	},
	{
		question: 'What does e^(pi*i) equal?',
		category: 'Math',
		answers: [ '0', '1', '-1', 'infinity', 'undefined' ],
		correctAnswer: '-1'
	},
	{
		question: 'What is Indiana Jones\' greatest fear?',
		category: 'Pop Culture',
		answers: [ 'Snakes', 'Crickets', 'Spiders', 'Heights', 'Nazis' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Snakes'
	},
	{
		question: 'William Harvey is known as the father of the. . .',
		category: 'Biology',
		answers: [ 'skeletal system', 'vascular and circulatory system', 'muscular system', 'excetory system', 'nervous system' ],
		correctAnswer: 'vascular and circulatory system'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following famous scientists does NOT have an element named after them.',
		category: 'Science',
		answers: [ 'Ernest Rutherford', 'Marie Curie', 'Dmitri Mendeleev', 'James Maxwell', 'Albert Einstein' ],
		correctAnswer: 'James Maxwell'
	},
	{
		question: 'The Hebrew expression "Mazel Tov" translates most closely to which of the following?',
		category: 'Language',
		answers: [ 'Good luck', 'Let\'s party', 'God bless', 'Happy birthday', 'May a piano not fall on your head' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Good luck'
	},
	{
		question: 'Indigo dye is predominately used in the coloring of. . . ',
		category: 'Manufacturing',
		answers: [ 'Hair', 'Food', 'Clothes', 'Glass', 'Paint' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Clothes'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is NOT a popular newspaper comic?',
		category: 'Pop Culture',
		answers: [ 'Zits', 'Pearls Before Swine', 'Dilbert', 'Garfield', 'Doghouse Diaries' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Doghouse Diaries'
	},
	{
		question: 'Caves are most likely to form in which type of rock?',
		category: 'Rocks',
		answers: [ 'Granite', 'Obsidian', 'Shale', 'Limestone', 'Pumice' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Limestone'
	},
	{
		question: 'Actuarially speaking omega (w) represents. . . ',
		category: 'Insurance',
		answers: [ 'Insurance', 'Risk', 'Birth', 'Midlife', 'Death' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Death'
	},
	{
		question: 'An abattoir is a. . .',
		category: 'Vocabulary',
		answers: [ 'person who runs an Abbey', 'person who builds furniture', 'slaughterhouse', 'school for boys', 'outhouse' ],
		correctAnswer: 'slaughterhouse'
	},
	{
		question: 'An ailurophile loves. . .',
		category: 'Vocabulary',
		answers: [ 'Beer', 'Seaweed', 'Rocks', 'Cats', 'Canals' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Cats'
	},
	{
		question: 'By mass approximately 47% of the earth is made up of which of the following elements?',
		category: 'Earth',
		answers: [ 'Sulfur', 'Oxygen', 'Silicon', 'Iron', 'Copper' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Oxygen'
	},
	{
		question: 'Who narrates the "Twilight Zone" TV series?',
		category: 'Pop Culture',
		answers: [ 'Conan O\'Brien', 'Bob Newhart', 'John Wayne', 'Mij Isrut', 'Rod Serling' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Rod Serling'
	},
	{
		question: 'Medically, what does hypokalemia refer to?',
		category: 'Medicine',
		answers: [ 'Eating too little kale', 'Low sodium', 'Low body temperature', 'Low potassium', 'Low blood sugar' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Low potassium'
	},
	{
		question: 'What is Holi?',
		category: 'Culture',
		answers: [ 'A city in Indonesia', 'A Pakistani delicacy', 'The Hindu spring festival', 'A medicinal herb', 'A famous palace in Thailand' ],
		correctAnswer: 'The Hindu spring festival'
	},
	{
		question: 'In which novel does Edmond Dantès swear revenge on the people who conspired to have him imprisoned?',
		category: 'French Literature',
		answers: [ 'Les Miserables', 'The Count of Monte Cristo', 'The Hunchback of Notre Dame', 'The Three Musketeers', 'In Search of Lost Time' ],
		correctAnswer: 'The Count of Monte Cristo'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is not written by Jules Verne, the famous French author?',
		category: 'Authors and Works',
		answers: [ 'Around the World In Eighty Days', 'Journey to the Center of the Earth', 'Twenty Thousand Leagues Under The Sea', 'In Search of the Castaways', 'In Search of Lost Time' ],
		correctAnswer: 'In Search of Lost Time'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is not considered to be a peripheral?',
		category: 'Computer Science',
		answers: [ 'A Mouse', 'A Monitor', 'A Keyboard', 'A Motherboard', 'Random Access Memory' ],
		correctAnswer: 'A Motherboard'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is not a piece that can be removed from Sam in the board game Operation?',
		category: 'Miscellaneous',
		answers: [ 'Adam\'s Apple', 'Got Your Nose', 'Broken Heart', 'Ankle Bone Connected to the Knee Bone', 'Bread Basket' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Got Your Nose'
	},
	{
		question: 'Blacksmiths work iron metal into different products, which historically included armor and weapons. With what metal do Redsmiths work?',
		category: 'Professions',
		answers: [ 'Tungsten', 'Germanium', 'Copper', 'Phosphorous', 'Cobalt' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Copper'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is a colloquial way to say "to reject" (as in rejecting a suitor) or "to jilt" in Spanish?',
		category: 'Spanish Vocabulary',
		answers: [ 'Dar las calabazas', 'Electrocutar', 'Recibir los dioses', 'Comer sus deseos', 'Abrazar sus abuelos' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Dar las calabazas'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is the name of the phenomenon that occurs when metals give off electrons when exposed to light?',
		category: 'Physics',
		answers: [ 'Bose-Einstein Condensation', 'Black-Body Radiation', 'Light Chipping', 'Photoelectric Effect', 'Zatch\'s Bell Curvature' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Photoelectric Effect'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is not a program that was part of the New Deal?',
		category: 'History',
		answers: [ 'Public Works Association', 'Civilian Conservation Corps', 'Environmental Protection Agency', 'Agricultural Adjustment Agency', ' National Recovery Administration' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Environmental Protection Agency'
	},
	{
		question: 'In which country did ketchup originate?',
		category: 'Condiments ',
		answers: [ 'USA', 'United Kingdom', 'Germany', 'China', 'Japan' ],
		correctAnswer: 'China'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following epic poems was originally written in Latin and tells the story of the founding of Rome?',
		category: 'Literature',
		answers: [ 'Aeneid', 'Iliad', 'Odyssey', 'Voyage of Argo', 'Paradise Lost' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Aeneid'
	},
	{
		question: 'Uptown Girl, We Didn\'t Start the Fire, and Only the Good Die Young are hit songs by which pop artist?',
		category: 'Music',
		answers: [ 'Sir Elton John', 'Billy Joel', 'Neil Young', 'Bruce Springsteen', 'Michael Jackson' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Billy Joel'
	},
	{
		question: 'The photon, or light particle, was developed by which famous physicist to explain the photoelectric effect?',
		category: 'Science',
		answers: [ 'Werner Heisenberg', 'Albert Einstein', 'Wolfgang Pauli', 'Max Planck', 'Ernst Mach' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Albert Einstein'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which thinker is credited with the idea of "Natural Rights" that formed the basis for the right to life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness present in the Declaration of Independence?',
		category: 'Philosophy',
		answers: [ 'David Hume', 'Immanuel Kant', 'John Locke', 'Gottfried Leibniz', 'Socrates' ],
		correctAnswer: 'John Locke'
	},
	{
		question: '"That which does not kill me, only makes me stronger." - A line present in popular songs by Kelly Clarkson and Kanye West was originally said by which man?',
		category: 'Aphorisms',
		answers: [ 'George Washington', 'John Dewey', 'Soren Kierkegaard', 'Friedrich Nietzsche', 'Erasmus' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Friedrich Nietzsche'
	},
	{
		question: 'Quixotic, an adjective derived from the protagonist of the famous Spanish novel "Don Quixote" means which of the following',
		category: 'Vocabulary',
		answers: [ 'Silly', 'Idealistic', 'Kind', 'Ugly', 'Strong' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Idealistic'
	},
	{
		question: 'Polders are areas of land reclaimed from the sea by building dikes and draining water. Which European country is especially associated with the construction of polders?',
		category: 'Geography',
		answers: [ 'Belgium', 'Poland', 'Lithuania', 'Norway', 'The Netherlands' ],
		correctAnswer: 'The Netherlands'
	},
	{
		question: 'The Soviets launched the first animal into orbit aboard Sputnik 2 on November 3, 1957. Laika, the animal, was of which species?',
		category: 'Space Exploration',
		answers: [ 'Chimpanzee', 'Dog', 'Rhesus Monkey', 'Gerbil', 'Cat' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Dog'
	},
	{
		question: 'Alan Turing, the famous computer scientist, became especially famous for helping to break which sophisticated Nazi code during WWII?',
		category: 'Codes',
		answers: [ 'Puzzle', 'Cryptograph', 'Enigma', 'Cipher', 'Head-Scratcher' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Enigma'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following cities is the capital of Morocco?',
		category: 'Geography',
		answers: [ 'Nairobi', 'Rabat', 'Cairo', 'Casablanca', 'Algiers' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Rabat'
	},
	{
		question: 'Which tests, often used in fields associated with psychology and psychiatry, are named after a Freudian psychoanalyst, and involve a subject\'s perception of inkblots on paper?',
		category: 'Psychology',
		answers: [ 'Holtzmann Tests', 'Rorschach Tests', 'Inkblot Tests', 'Neato Black Spot Tests', 'Psyhological General Tests' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Rorschach Tests'
	},
	{
		question: 'The Stern-Gerlach experiment, which, in part, discovered electron spin, is named for scientists from what country?',
		category: 'Geographical Science',
		answers: [ 'Russia', 'Denmark', 'Norway', 'Germany', 'Ireland' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Germany'
	},
	{
		question: 'In WWII which country did the Germans have their main U-boat base?',
		category: 'History',
		answers: [ 'Germany', 'France', 'Spain', 'Sweden', 'Norway' ],
		correctAnswer: 'France'
	},
	{
		question: 'At which temperature does the Celsius and Fahreinheit scale refer to the same absolute temperature?',
		category: 'Science',
		answers: [ '100 degrees', '60 degrees', '0 degrees', '-40 degrees', '-120 degrees' ],
		correctAnswer: '-40 degrees'
	},
	{
		question: 'Who wrote the famous book Crime and Punishment?',
		category: 'Literature',
		answers: [ 'Fyodor Dostoyevsky', 'Lev Tolstoy', 'Anton Chekhov', 'Alexander Pushkin', 'Makin Gorky' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Fyodor Dostoyevsky'
	},
	{
		question: 'Controlling the process of transpiration to facilitate a cellular process, this structure is found on the epidermis of the organism.',
		category: 'Pores',
		answers: [ 'Cuticle', 'Lumen', 'Follicle', 'Stoma', 'Parenchyma' ],
		correctAnswer: 'Stoma'
	}
];